We're here...
Yes, we are.
What's the matter, Brother?
What do you think the matter is?
Once again, I'm going to have to hear the Colonel's long-winded, snide remarks.
"You struck out on the
Philosopher's Stone at Liore, huh?"
"Just how much of the military's budget
are you going to spend
on this fool's errand
before you're satisfied?"
"Uh-oh, I don't see
Edward-kun around."
"I'm right here!"
"Sorry, sorry, I didn't see you there
behind my paperwork.
Ha ha ha ha!"
But then, like you said, we're here now,
so I guess I've got no choice.
Let's go, Al.
Huh? Al?
Al!
Sorry, sorry!
What are you up to?
What?
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
What's the matter, Breda?
H-Havoc, watch out!
O-Over there!
Over there!
What do we have here?
I believe it's a dog.
A carnivorous canine. The scientific name is—
That's not what I was asking, Warrant Officer Falman.
I beg your pardon, Lt. Hawkeye.
I'm terribly sorry.
I found him this morning.
Master Sgt. Fuery...
You're keeping him?
I wish I could, but as I'm sure you know, Lt.
Havoc,
animals are not permitted in the dormitories.
You can't keep him here
in the office because of that.
He was shivering out in the rain, and I felt so sorry for him.
Will anyone else keep him?
I'm also in the dorms.
No way. I hate dogs.
Okay, I guess I'll take him.
I do like dogs, after all.
Thank you so much, Lieutenant!
I hear they're good
when stir-fried.
Out here in the eastern country,
they're raised for food.
The redder ones in particular—
Let's look for another master.
Right.
I'm kidding!
Um, are you busy?
Edward-kun, Alphonse-kun,
you're back?
Was that...
Why, you...
Al, come here!
Edward-kun, your report!
I'll go see the Colonel directly!
We don't have capacity
or the conditions to keep him.
You can't just go around picking up animals.
But he was shivering out in the rain.
I can keep him, right?
No!
Go drop him off
where you found him.
Brother, you idiot!
You're not human!
Don't run!
Think about the poor cat!
I know! I know!
It sounds like you really did
quite a number on all of this.
You mean, the town of Liore?
You're the one who gave me the information on the fake Philosopher's Stone, right?
But I never told you to drive
the Minister from his position.
As a result, the town has come under the rule of the Eastern Command Center, right?
Hey, don't tell me that's what
you were after in the first place!
I heard that in Xenotime, the great landowner Mugear has gone missing
and that his mansion has collapsed.
Yeah? Where was this Xenotime again?
I wonder if I could get you to submit a report on the red water as well.
There was also an inquiry from the police in the tourist resort of Aquroya.
Is it true that Psiren's
unmasked face is beautiful?
What you're trying to say is that
you can tell everything we do, right?
Fullmetal, why don't you try settling down already?
Are you telling me to become one of your toadies?
We ourselves have a purpose.
The Philosopher's Stone, huh?
But it's been three years,
and you still haven't found it.
I'll find it, no matter what!
Colonel, do you know
the name Marcoh?
He's a doctor and an alchemist who showed up in Xenotime five years ago.
Apparently, he cured the poisoning caused by the red water,
something no one else could cure, with some kind of alchemy.
I figured that the military would at least know the name of someone that skilled.
I don't recall it.
But I will check it out.
Colonel...
This is an unexpected pleasure, Brigadier General.
As of today, we'll be using this office as a temporary Central Command Center.
A temporary Central Command Center?
What a hassle this must be!
There, at ease, at ease.
Führer, your Excellency!
Henceforth, His Excellency the Führer,
and the chief command personnel under him,
will be observing the Eastern Region.
Look at all those chains!
Those are the silver watches that
show that they're State Alchemists.
Which means that everyone here is a State Alchemist?
Look, look!
Elicia can ride a tricycle now!
She follows me around everywhere like this!
You're the same as ever, Major.
I've got more. Wanna see?
Ah, no.
But you know, if you're going to come see us, you could've said something ahead of time.
But I wanted to see the surprised look on Mustang's face!
Oh, and I'm a Lt. Colonel now.
I'm in charge of investigations at the Court-Martial Office.
Then you should be in Central, shouldn't you?
What can I do?
All of the prominent bigwigs are
trying to run away from Central—
I mean—never mind.
Er, how have you been doing...
with the Philosopher's Stone?
We might be getting closer.
Right now, I'm searching for
a man named Doctor Marcoh.
But the Colonel
won't tell me anything.
Are you sure he
just doesn't know?
Nah, that bastard is definitely hiding something.
You just said "Marcoh," didn't you?
Brigadier General Grand...
The Iron Blood Alchemist...
By "Marcoh,"
do you mean the deserter Marcoh?
Six years ago, many State Alchemists
were called up to the Eastern Rebellion.
However, Marcoh deserted the battlefield before it came to an end
and has been missing ever since.
Deserter?
Don't know him.
Doctor Marcoh... Doctor Marcoh...
Damn!
Sure enough, all records of him
have been erased!
At this point, I guess I'll just have to
flatten the Colonel and beat it out of him!
Flatten him, Brother?
Are you still...
Well, you know, it hasn't stopped raining yet...
Yo! I forgot to mention
something important earlier.
What is it?!
W-Well...
because of the situation,
this year's assessments will temporarily be held here rather than at Central.
Assessments?
You mean the assessments to renew certifications for State Alchemists?
I'll let you know later about the provisions and such—
Hang on, Major.
That's Lt. Colonel!
In that case, I have a way I'd like to try handling the assessment.
Right?
Battle assessment?
Is there such a thing?
The alchemist conducts a mock battle,
and the contest itself is what gets assessed.
And Edward himself
requested to do this?
And what's more, he nominated the Colonel to go against?
Still, if they went at it seriously,
which one do you think is stronger?
That'd be the Colonel, wouldn't it?
Nah, you can't take
Fullmetal too lightly, either.
But when you think about the stories of the Colonel's activities during the Eastern Rebellion...
Why would Edward-san propose such a thing?
I heard that he gave the
condition that if he won,
the Colonel would have to keep a cat.
A cat?
Well, I guess we can't have
the Colonel take this guy, huh?
Yes?
A dog.
How nice!
Really?
Of course!
They are loyal above all else!
They follow their master's orders unconditionally!
Treat them cruelly,
and they don't complain!
And they don't require a salary!
Indeed, they are servants to mankind!
How nice! I love dogs!
By the way, Colonel, are you
going to accept Edward's challenge?
I can't very well go
all-out against a child.
It will be a shame that I cannot display my true valor.
Sounds interesting.
I will permit this battle assessment.
B-But...
You can use the entire parade grounds.
That way, we won't have to worry about damage to the surrounding area.
It's not as though you
weren't sure of yourself.
Go on, fight the Fullmetal Alchemist.
For now, I'm just going to
dutifully obey their words.
At least until I achieve the rank of Führer and gain absolute power over the military.
I think you might want to be more discreet about such inappropriate declarations.
Still, what could your purpose be in saying something so presumptuous?
That's a stupid question.
Once I become Führer...
all female military personnel will wear miniskirts!
Colonel! I will follow you to the ends of the earth!
All right!
What pleasure!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to the Eastern
Command Center Festival!
And incidentally, this is...
my daughter,
who turned three this year!
Elicia! Elicia!
And now, we'll move directly to today's main event!
In the red corner,
the Flame Alchemist,
Roy Mustang!
You ogre!
Only get yourself promoted, will you?
Return my girlfriend!
In the blue corner,
the Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric!
Huh? Where? Where?
Wow, he's so small!
I can't see him!
Is he a grade-schooler?
Good luck, bean sprout!
Small?!
Don't call me small!
Calm down, Brother.
Fine, then.
Today is a great day,
when I bust the Colonel's
pompous mug in front of everyone!
But, Brother,
we're indebted to the Colonel.
He's overworked me,
saying he'd let our secret out!
So, what's your strategy?
Pop him with my fist!
The assessment doesn't matter to me.
If I win, you're giving me your
information on Doctor Marcoh.
That, and you're
taking care of the cat.
Very well, then...
Ready...
Fight!
You're too slow!
Give me some warning, dammit!
"A soldier favors foolish haste above cleverness."
That means press the battle quickly, and end the battle quickly.
Those flames are
appearing out of thin air!
Ah, this is the first time you've seen the Colonel do that?
His right glove is made of a special fabric,
called ignition cloth.
If you rub it hard, it creates sparks.
All that's left is for him to adjust the density of oxygen in the air,
and "boom!"
Sorry!
Now, then...
It sure is hard to hit
such a small target!
Don't call me small!
"If your opponent is of choleric temper,
seek to irritate him."
Don't fall for the enemy's taunts.
You've gotta be kidding!
Perhaps I overdid it a bit.
There you are!
Oh, no!
Now you can't shoot
any more flames!
You're done for!
Yow...
"All war is deception." Even sneak attacks make for worthy strategy, Fullmetal.
Do it!
You need not even ask.
That's far enough!
That was a magnificent fight!
We are honored by
your words of praise!
Hold on!
We're not through yet!
Mm-hmm,
but if you go any further,
it will be tougher to
tidy up afterward, won't it?
They've got no choice. Both of them were ordered to fix everything.
This is why I didn't want to do this.
Colonel, why did you hold back?
Your last shot—
you should've had the timing for it.
This goes back many years now,
but there was something
called the Ishbalan Rebellion.
In the east, when the Ishbalans clashed with the military?
I saw... many unpleasant things...
Doctor Marcoh,
who deserted the battlefield,
was the most sensible man among us.
I still think so, even now.
Is that why you kept quiet about him?
But then, perhaps you ought to see Marcoh.
He's alive?!
Colonel, I still haven't heard the reason why you stopped on that last shot.
Nah,
never mind.
If there are no other
candidates to keep him,
I will take him.
Really?!
Now, now, just because you're relieved...
My discipline is strict.
Come on now, the bathroom is over here.
Got that, Black Hayate?
Black Hayate?
About the town of Liore,
in Ed's report...
Did you know that General Hakuro's detachment had been dispatched there?
I hear there's a terrible
civil war going on.
Ed wrote that the Minister had fallen,
and that the people would likely open their eyes.
The Minister is doing fine.
I understand he's inciting the citizens to wage war against the military.
I can't be sure whether or not it's the same minister that Ed defeated, though.
Are you going to send Ed in again to investigate?
He believes he's saved a town.
We can let him believe that.
He'll find out on his own sometime.
We've gotten the information on Marcoh from the Colonel.
We can't very well ask him to take care of this too.
It would go against the
Principle of Equivalent Exchange.
Yes, it would.
Sorry, but right now,
this is all we can do.
Isn't it about time you told me?
You're not here to observe us.
The bigwigs conned the Führer
into fleeing here.
In Central alone, there are already five State Alchemists and staff
who have been killed.
East City...
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 14: "Destruction's Right Hand"
Even if all of the State Alchemists are your enemies,
I won't allow you to kill Brother!